Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lorinczlorand-919a3422 (LinkedIn) stackoverflow.com/users/966929/ lori (Other)

Top Skills

Java

Hibernate

Spring Boot

Languages

German (Professional Working)
Italian (Elementary)
English (Full Professional)

Lorincz Lorand

Freelanceing at MHP – A Porsche Company Romania

Summary

Software Developer with experience and/or knowledge in the following programming languages, software and frameworks: Java8, Spring, JPA/Hibernate, Jersey, PostgreSQL, Coffeescript, AngularJS, Docker, Kubernetes, Camunda, Pentaho, SWT, JFACE, C#, .NET, XAML, WP8, WinRT, Ruby on Rails, html, css, javascript, Bootstrap, MSSQL, .NET, C#, oData, XML, XSLT, XSD, LINQ, WCF, Adobe Flash, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premier Pro, Adobe After Effects.

Foreign languages: English - Advanced German - Advanced Hungarian - Medium Italian - Beginner

Experience

MHP – A Porsche Company
Freelancing
June 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Fullstack developer on a Planning Tool using Eclipse RCP, Spring Boot, OracleDB. Responsabilities were maintenance and development of the Eclipse RCP Client, migrating the old SAP based backend to a Spring Boot backend and developing the backend for a new web client. Migrate SVN to Gitlab, Jenkins to Gitlab CI/CD. Desing the new webservies according to REST best practices. Refactor business logic from fat-client to the backend. Responsible for converting User Stories to technical specifications.

Freelancing 8 years 3 months

Freelancer Software Development - business partner EBS April 2010 - June 2018 (8 years 3 months) Cluj-Napoca Worked as a Full-Stack Developer on a Web Application for a Swiss Company. The application is an extendable Platform that manages documents, workflows, ETL Transformations, dashboards, reports and has also a machine learning module. Technologies used: AngularJS, Coffeescript, Java 8, Spring Boot, Jersey, PostgreSQL, JPA with Hibernate, Docker, Kubernetes. Started as a developer and later on took more responsibilities including SCRUM Master and in some instances Technical Lead. Responsible for converting User Stories to technical solutions.

Worked as a Front-End Developer on a Eclipse RCP based Planning Application using SWT and JFace for a big automotive company in Germany. My role is to develop new features based mostly on functional specs using Eclipse RCP, Java, SWT, JFace and Jasper Reports. Daily interaction with the German client (German language.) and occasional business trips in Germany. Tools used in development process: Eclipse, iReport, Ant, SVN and Jira.

Worked on an internal Windows Store & Windows Phone 8 App. I took part in developing the the server-side application and the Windows 8 and Windows Phone 8 clients using C#, WCF Data Services, Windows Store Apps API, Windows Phone 8 and MVVM Light.

Web Developer May 2013 - February 2014 (10 months)

Developing a Taxi Management Web Application for a U.S. Client, using Ruby on Rails, WebSockets, LeafletJs, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap and javascript. Some of the features of the application include, ticket management, finances, statistics, driver position tracking and display using a map, chat functionalities and notifications.

My role in this project was to analyse and implement the clients functional requirements.

Centric IT Web Developer July 2009 - March 2010 (9 months) Cluj-Napoca, Romania

Development of a web tracker like googleAnalytics or statCounter, using .NET, SQL, javascript, webservices(WCF), development of the UI using html, css, javascript, photoshop and different API's(GoogleMaps, jFlot).

Development of a IP locator using html, css, javascript, .NET, Google Maps API and a IP database API.

Development of a universal connector and convertor for different data sources(XML, Excel, MSSQL, MySQL, ORACLE, MSAcces, txt, EDI etc.) using .NET, webservices(WCF), XSL and XSD.

Nokia Intern June 2009 - July 2009 (2 months) Cluj-Napoca, Romania

IT Assistance for the Security Department.

Design and content for prints and presentation movies regarding production security, using Adobe Photoshop and Flash.

Testing security equipments and systems.

Remarul 16 Februarie Programer assistant July 2006 - July 2007 (1 year 1 month) Cluj-Napoca, Romania

Supervise the functioning and correct use of company software and help company programmers in coding and daily software maintenance.

Successful integration of new software in the company work-plan.

Development of useful software for the marketing department.

Education

Faculty of Electronics and Telecomunications, Telecomunication and Information Technologysection, English, Cluj Napoca Engineer, Telecomunications, Information Technology, Software Development · (2006 - 2010)

Informatics Highschool, Tiberiu Popoviciu, Cluj Napoca Praogrammin Assistant, Programming, Mathematics · (2002 - 2006)